

Hartford City, IN United States 2605829842 baldrich@protonmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Lead Go Engineer and Backend Architect with 9 years of experience driving innovation across industries like 911 telecommunications, blockchain, transportation, finance and credit. Led multiples teams to develop secure, high-performance backend systems, related to identity, authentication/authorization, and finance. Interested in growth technologies and building production ready products from the ground up.

SKILLS

• Go

Javascript

Docker

AWS RDS

• AWS SQS

AWS ECR

Mongo DB Atlas

• Git

Helm

Blockchain

OIDC

Cryptography

MySQL

Datadog

Typescript

Haskell

Kubernetes

AWS IAM

AWS Route53

AWS KMS

Twilio

Gitlab

Terraform

GRPC

WebAuthn

EntGo

Postgres

• Grafana

Swift

Python

AWS EKS

AWS Elasticache

AWS SES

Mongo DB

Telesign

· Gitlab-CI

Jenkins

OAuth2

DPoP

Linux

Redis

Prometheus

EXPERIENCE

Lead Go Engineer - Backend Architect

April 2021 - Current

Equifax/Cognizant | Remote

- · Ownership over several high profile projects around digital-identity, authentication, authorization, and tokens.
- Ownership and lead engineer for Equifax's next generation digital-identity-service.
- Ownership and lead engineer for Equifax's internal token issuance service.
- Ownership and lead engineer over Equifax's next generation authentication and authorization service.
- Ownership and lead over supporting customer facing SDKs.
- Built many of these services from the ground up using technologies such as demonstrating proof of possession, webauthn, split tokens, and more.

- Ownership over all infrastructure and SRE related projects.
- Built and maintained CI/CD, EKS clusters, deployment environments, and utilities.
- Built infrastructure in a decentralized manner using smart contracts and IPFS.
- · Built several backend services related to analytics of a decentralized exchange using Go and Haskell.
- Ran stand ups and ticket organization and creation.

Senior Go Engineer - GoTezos Library Owner

January 2020 - December 2021

Brice Aldrich Development LLC | Remote

- · Built and maintained an open source library interfacing with the Tezos blockchain RPC in Go.
- Built cryptographic functions to create wallets, sign operations, and verify operations.
- Built structures and tooling around reading blocks and smart contracts on the chain.
- Built batch payment tools to facilitate payments for proof of stake businesses.
- Built infrastructure related tooling to deploy a proof of stake operation.
- Ran a proof of stake service where at it's peak had several million in assets represented.
- Received a large grant to continue open source development over a year.

Lead/Senior Go Engineer - Core Architecture

October 2019 - May 2020

OneCause | Indianapolis

- Built and maintained core Go libraries central to the microservices that facilitated payments.
- · Built and maintained core Go libraries central to the microservices that facilitated donor auctions and billing.
- Advised and collaborated with the general architecture team aiding in decisions on over all product architecture.
- Worked with junior developers on progressing their skills and careers.

Golang Security Engineer - Cloud Identity

March 2019 - October 2019

Apple | Remote

- Built and helped design apples internal authentication service similar to AWS IAM.
- Helped design policy based management solutions to authenticate internal apple customers into their kubernetes clusters and development environments.
- · Helped build and design CLI utilities related to authentication and managing clusters.
- Used technologies such as oauth2, oidc, grpc, go, and opa.

Part Time Software Engineer Contractor

January 2019 - December 2019

Tezos Marigold | Remote

- Built and designed supporting development tooling around a higher level smart contract language called LIGO.
- Built syntax highlighting for the various forms of LIGO.
- Built a simple language server and vscode plugin for the various formats of LIGO.
- Tested LIGO as a language and deployed test smart contracts to the tezos blockchain.

Backend Go Engineer

November 2018 - March 2019

Transworks | Fort Wayne IN

- · Optimized existing Go code by introducing concurrency models.
- Optimized database queries using legacy technologies related to the railroad transportation industry.
- Implemented requested features end to end by collaborating with all team members.
- Helped facilitate project direction and manage service now.

Research And Development Engineer

May 2015 - November 2018

INdigital | Fort Wayne IN

- Collaborate, design, and develop proof of concept technologies related to 911 telecommunications and routing.
- Build out developer tooling using virtualization and automation tools.
- Built protocol parsers for specific binary data formats and telecom related protocols.
- Built and improved existing systems related to routing.
- Helped with feature work and supporting tools related to text to 911 products.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Purdue University - Fort Wayne, Fort Wayne